# Batyrzhan **Iusup-Akhunov**

"Not to be clever, but to try to be."

## **Summary**

Current Business Analyst at Tinkoff Russia and Software engineer at FRC CSC lab (RAS). 3+ years experience specializing in the software development for applied sciences and process automation. Also 2+ years experience as Control theory course instructor. Gigachad maths enjoyer who loves to interpret various processes in terms of mathematics. Interested in complex problems that require different approaches and interpretations when solving them. Willing to explore new existing methods and, if necessary, develop new approaches to solve the problems posed.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

**Tinkoff** Moscow, Russia

BUSINESS ANALYST (BA/BI), CUSTOMER SERVICE DEPARTMENT

- Mar. 2022 PRESENT · Gather business requirements for the customer service department and provide options for solutions. Manage the consensus solution process.
- Analyze the needs of customers. Create and develop new business workflows for Customer service department.
- Improve the routing of customer requests between and within business units.
- Create interactive dashboards and reports.

## Federal Research Center, Computer Science and Control, Russian Academy of Sciences

Moscow, Russia

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Develop open-source library for solving optimal control problems. Tech stack: SymPy, NumPy, SciPy

Nov. 2021 - PRESENT

Provide advanced UI with high UX. Tech stack: LaTeX, ANTLR-4, HyperNetX/NetworkX, jinja2

## Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology, Department of Control and Applied **Mathematics**

Moscow, Russia

COURSE INSTRUCTOR, OPTIMAL CONTROL THEORY AND APPLICATIONS

Sep. 2021 - PRESENT

- Improvement of the course syllabus toward applied methods of control theory.
- Structuring course information for easy use by students.

### **Institute of System Programming, Russian Academy of Sciences**

Moscow, Russia

INTERN, NATURAL LANGUAGE PROCESSING

Oct. 2020 - Jun. 2021

- Implementing existing software knowledge base population methods, by description in article.
- Improving triplets extraction using language modeling

# Writing\_

Co-Author

## Article, Support system for modeling socioeconomic processes based on an open source platform

MIPT proceedings

• Open-source Python library to provide solution for optimal control problems.

Dec. 2022

# Thesis, Modeling and Simulation of Financial Bubbles in Illiquid Market of Rational **Agents**

MACSPro'21

Co-Author • Developed financial bubbles modeling system. Dec. 2021

## Education

## MIPT (Moscow Institute of Science and Technology)

Moscow, Russia

BACHELOR DEGREE IN APPLIED MATHEMATICS AND PHYSICS

Sep. 2017 - Aug. 2021

• Area of study: Software developing, ML Engineering, NLP (Natural language processing)

#### MIPT (Moscow Institute of Science and Technology)

Moscow, Russia

MASTERS DEGREE IN APPLIED MATHEMATICS AND PHYSICS

Sep. 2021 - Aug. 2023

• Area of study: Optimization, Optimal control theory, Process Automation